Sorry, let's get a move on
because I don't have much time.
No, no, don't worry. This'll
only take a few minutes.
Okay.
We are recording.
The World Rally Championship
has grown in popularity
in recent years
to become the number one
TV sport in the world.
Drivers like Walter Roöhrl
and the Queen of Speed,
Michele Mouton, have
become household names.
This week we turn our attention
to the key players off the
track, the team managers.
We're joined by team
manager, Cesare Fiorio,
hailing from Turin, Italy.
Fiorio has led both Fiat
and Lancia to victory.
Mr. Fiorio, pleased
to meet you.
My pleasure. But
please, call me Cesare.
Cesare, I'd like to
start by asking you
what drew you to rallying?
Well, probably because I
love the speed and the risk.
Is that not true of
any other motor sport?
Oh, rallying is very different.
Rallying belongs to everyone.
Let's say it's a
democratic sport.
What do you mean by that?
It's very difficult
to explain rally.
You have to live it.
You see, the spectators, they feel
the same speed as the drivers,
because you know, you
race in your own town.
The cars hurtle past
your children's school,
the cafe where you used to have
your coffee, normal places.
Rallying isn't as
well known in the US.
Could you tell our
listeners what your role is?
Let's say rallying is like a war,
and I'm the commander of an army.
The world championship
is made up of 13 trials
divided into grueling stages,
long transfers, by day, by night,
in dust, sand, snow, rain, you know.
But what is it
exactly that you do?
What I do is to make decisions
in the shortest possible time.
So if we look at the results
of last year's championship,
we could say that your rival,
Roland Gumpert, made
better decisions than you.
What does Audi have
that you don't?
Well, an entire industrial
and financial sector
that supports research
and development.
Do you know the four-wheel
drive is derived
from military technology?
They really did bring the army.
Rallying is a dangerous sport.
Does anything frighten you?
Yeah.
One thing.
Losing.
Audi is leading in Portugal.
They're ahead of everyone on the
overall constructor standings.
In the cold Finnish night,
the German Audi is
humiliating Italy
in terms of technological
development.
THE REVOLUTIONARY
The Audi team lead by Roland
Gumpert is unstoppable.
Lancia shows all its limits.
Audi beats Lancia on all tracks.
It's a pleasure to see
them racing at full speed.
Once again, Audi is racing
towards a new victory.
♪ 25 pounds of tenderness ♪
♪ In each and every touch ♪
♪ 25 pounds of
understanding my man ♪
♪ And I don't want
to worry too much ♪
As the new world rally season begins
there are many reasons to believe
that this is going to
be an amazing contest.
Audi, Lancia, Opel, and
the other manufacturers
will be fighting a
new sort of battle.
Fans around the
world cannot wait.
The contest opens with the legendary
Monte Carlo as it does every year.
Now over to the traffic news.
Yes, Mr Gumpert, immediately.
Stop!
Again!
- It's running better than last year.
- Perfect!
Almost perfect.
Start again!
Sir, they've
dismantled the Audi.
Look how wonderful
this joint is.
The transmission has a differential
that splits the pair at 50%.
And it does so using two axles,
one below and one above...
with two coaxial shafts,
one inside the other.
When the Germans do things, they
definitely do them well, eh?
Not always.
Do you know how to tell
German wine from vinegar?
- No.
- Read the labels.
We need to develop four-wheel
drive technology as well.
But we don't have the time.
We need something like that.
Short wheelbase, very
light, mid-engine.
The Stratos could fly.
Sir,
- they're waiting at the meeting.
- I'll be right there.
- Ennio, take this.
- Yes.
- You come up with me.
- Sir, like this, I'm...
Yes, like that! I'll wait
for you upstairs. Hurry up!
- Good morning, Avvocato.
- Good morning.
Do you want to know a
curious thing, Mr. Fiorio?
Do you know what my grandson asked
me for as a birthday present?
An Audi Quattro.
These Germans are good.
Work hard!
And good luck.
It's impossible
to beat them now.
We don't have this winning car.
We're too far behind
on the all-wheel drive.
The technological gap with
the Germans is frightening.
Even if we started work tomorrow
and doubled the R&D budget,
we wouldn't get a
competitive car.
It'll take at least
two, three years.
Forgive me, sir. With the money
for the racing department,
we could run a powerful
advertising campaign.
If you want to reconsider our
proposal, it's on page three.
Excuse me, but we can't do
anything with happy families
leaving for their summer
vacation in a Lancia.
The only possible
advert is to win.
No one wants to buy
a car that loses.
Fiorio, I'm not asking you
to win, but to lose well.
But you can't lose well.
You can only lose badly.
I want to win this world
championship, whatever it takes.
Ennio.
This is a plan of
the Audi Quattro.
Longitudinal,
five-cylinder engine.
Maximum torque of
285 Newton/meters.
Central differential, rear
axle identical to the front,
except it's rotated 180 degrees
so it can interface with
the transmission shaft.
Incredible road holding.
It sticks to the ground.
You have to scrape the
asphalt off the wheels.
Apparently unbeatable, but...
2,900 lbs.
They're heavy. Very heavy.
- They'll see this in Greece.
- One thing still isn't clear.
Which car are we
taking to Greece?
The Monte Carlo Beta project.
Mid-engine.
Two-wheel drive.
Rear-wheel drive.
A racing car.
Of course...
on snow and dirt
roads, we'll lose.
But on asphalt we'll be light.
Very light. We'll be flying.
And who's going to drive this
car? Will you drive it, Fiorio?
No.
The best driver will.
Morning.
Walter,
it's Cesare.
Ah, Cesare.
Nice to see you.
Can I take off this?
Take it off, yeah.
Sorry if I didn't tell
you that I was coming,
but you know. What
happened to your face?
Ah, I spent a lifetime
telling people
not to walk in the mountains
with their hand
in their pockets.
And then I.
You did it.
- What are you doing here?
- Nothing.
I, I came to visit
this young pilot.
Very good driver, very talented.
And then I said to myself,
well, I'm very close
to Walter's house,
and why don't you go to
say hello? And here I am,
My bees.
- I see.
- They're strange, huh?
I mean, they're not domesticated
and they're not wild.
They're a mix.
They're creatures capable
of maintaining relationships
with humans without
losing their freedom.
Isn't that wonderful?
Incredible creatures.
So did you, did you sign
up with someone yet?
I've had lots of offers,
I'm weighing them up.
And you, how's the
development coming along?
You've got a competitive
car this year?
Yeah. Special car.
Very incredible car.
Central engine, very powerful,
light car using very
special materials, yeah.
You'll see.
Four wheel drive?
No, no, no, no.
Two wheel drive.
You can't beat them
with a normal car.
Yes we can.
No you can't.
You wanna try the honey?
No. No actually I have to go.
I'm very late, I have to
to drive back to Turin.
- Nice to see you.
- Good to see you.
Cesare, the young
driver, what's his name?
Oh, it's a German name.
I forgot, it's very difficult
name, can't remember. See you.
See you.
What did he want from you?
Guess.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
May I have a coffee and
some croissants please?
We don't have croissants,
but I can bring you
some bread if you wish.
Okay, some bread. Thanks.
Did you remember the name of the
young driver you came to see?
Yes, of course. Kurt.
Oh. Him, you mean?
Listen Walter, let's be
honest with each other. Hm?
You have to come to try this car.
We can win only if you drive it.
I really don't want to
compete in this championship.
You know what it is, Cesare?
I'm tired.
Tired of photographers,
hotels, autographs.
I'm tired of winning, but
that's all you care about.
Yeah, it's true. What's
wrong with it? That's my job.
Give me one good reason
why I should accept.
Because we are the underdogs,
and it's perfect if you're
tired of winning, isn't it?
- Are you staying overnight sir?
- No, sir's leaving.
Yes, it's good.
- What is it?
- Zero-forty.
I would try another test
and reduce the tire
pressure to 1.7.
- I'd lighten the clutch a little.
- OK.
Very good, Marco. Well done.
Zero-forty. Excellent time.
Good.
- Does it have a name?
- Yeah.
0' 37" is the new track record.
Nice car.
Do you like it or not?
Powerful engine, light,
great road holding.
Goes exactly where
I want it to go.
I like a shoe made to
measure for my foot, but
it's very fragile.
On asphalt, no one will beat it.
On dirt roads and
snow, it's a coffin.
Do you accept or not?
I'll only do the races I love,
Monte Carlo, Acropolis, New Zealand.
Five, six races at the most.
Hey, wait a second. What do
you mean five, six races?
There are 12. I want to win the
whole title, not half of it.
- Six races. Take it or leave it.
- But why?
Take it or leave it.
Well, what did Roöhrl say?
He agreed! He agreed!
Go, Kurt!
Allow me to introduce
the new Lancia 037.
1,996 cubic centimeters
of displacement,
310 horsepower,
volumetric compressor,
rear-wheel drive,
with two-wheel drive.
Mr. Fiorio, to have a
four-wheel drive like the Audi,
you'll need two cars, ja?
Sir, we have a problem.
We don't have enough cars.
Nicolas Muller,
Frankfurter Allgemeine.
As you know, to enter the
world championship, the rule is
that every automaker
has to produce
a minimum of 200 models to
be placed on the market.
So?
Even if we go at full speed
on the production lines
we won't manage
to make them all.
The inspection's tomorrow.
- How many do we have?
- 103.
But we need 200.
103.
101, 102.
- How many?
- 103.
- 103?
- Yes.
- Where are the others?
- Eh, this parking lot's full.
They're in another parking lot.
Another parking lot? Let's go,
we have other things to do.
- Let's go, now. All right?
- Yes, let's go, it's nearby.
We'll take the car and
go. It's nearby, come.
The usual Italian chaos.
Italians! Always the same.
There's a bit of traffic.
- What now?
- What is it? It's all blocked.
It's blocked. Is the parking
lot still a distance away?
Half an hour. But
I have an idea.
Let's stop. There's a little
restaurant there, we'll stop
and have a quick lunch, then
we'll go to the parking lot.
That way in the meantime...
the traffic will clear a bit.
Yes, but quickly. We
don't have a lot of time!
Of course, I promise.
So, for starters today we have
agnolotti, very fresh, sir...
Or a nice risotto
with white truffle.
Tomato noodles.
Or we can make a panissa.
Panissa? How do I
translate panissa?
OK, whatever, do a selection,
a bit of everything.
- Red wine?
- Yes, Barolo.
Barolo. Red wine, all right.
- We don't have much time.
- We won't be long.
- I'm going to choose the wine.
- This way, sir.
Right, the Barolos are here.
I'll go to the kitchen, and have
everything prepared very quickly,
- as you wish, quickly.
- No, you need to take your time.
All right? Take your
time. Take your time.
Good.
Very good.
Now we need to go. Shall we go?
- Let's finish eating and go.
- Yes, let's finish and then go.
Alright, take your time.
Finish calmly and then we'll
go. I'm going to the toilet.
95... 96...
And 97.
Plus 103, makes 200.
OK, Fiorio, that's OK.
We have to go, our plane's
waiting. Shall we go?
Welcome to the opening of
the 51st Monte Carlo Rally.
30 special stages of seven
days of 10 transfers.
Each car arriving late the
time check will be penalized.
Beware they are transferring
from one stage to another
because it's still part of
the race, so let them pass.
♪ She'll only come
out at night ♪
♪ The lean and hungry type ♪
♪ Nothing is new, I've
seen her here before ♪
♪ Watching and waiting ♪
♪ Oh she's sitting with you
but her eyes are on the door ♪
♪ So many have paid to see ♪
♪ What, do you think
you get it for free ♪
♪ The woman is wild ♪
♪ A she-cat tamed by
the purr of a Jaguar ♪
♪ Money's the matter ♪
♪ If you're in it for love
you ain't gonna get to far ♪
♪ Oh here she comes ♪
♪ Watch out boy
she'll chew you up ♪
♪ Oh here she comes ♪
A drink please.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- The same as the lady.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Hi, Cesare.
- Honey, do you know who this is?
- No.
Cesare Fiorio.
He's the team manager of Lancia,
and he's a very brave man.
In fact, he's so brave that
he thinks he can challenge us
without a four-wheel drive.
- Slow and steady wins the race
- Four are better than two.
Don't you feel cold?
No, I'm used to it.
By the way, I
checked the weather.
It's going to snow tomorrow.
So don't forget
your snow chains.
- Champagne, please.
- Yes.
Tastes better with
ice, don't you think?
- Cheers.
Thank you.
- Is that salt?
- Yes, it's salt.
- Is this OK?
- Yes, sir.
Go, go!
Go, come on.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I imagine you're very busy,
but honestly it's
really dangerous.
I was driving, and
there's ice, snow...
You can't drive on it. Can
you do something, please?
Yes, I totally
understand the situation.
Give me a minute and I'll
deal with it right away.
Thank you.
Hey, guys! There's a
lot of ice up there.
Let's put the
studded tires on, go!
- We'll put them on as well.
- OK.
And here is Walter Roöhrl,
Prince of Monte Carlo and
reigning world champion,
driving the Lancia 037.
Great favorite this year on
the four wheel drive Audi,
Hannu Mikkola, the Flying Finn.
But the fabulous Porsche.
This is not Formula
one, this is rally.
Winner in 1978 in the legendary
Lancia Stratos, Markku Alén.
They are changing
the studded tires.
I repeat, they are
changing the studded tires.
Shit!
The noodle munchers tricked us!
Nice idea that, changing the
tires and removing the snow.
I didn't think about that.
Do you have any other ideas for
the rest of the championship?
Well, I'll do whatever the
regulations allow me to do.
- Because you read them?
- Yes, of course.
You should know them better
than me because you wrote them.
What do you insinuate?
No, I will never allow
myself to insinuate anything.
But it's curious that
when you would just ready
with four-wheel drive,
a footnote was inserted
in regulations book
that opened world championship
up to four-wheel drives.
But of course, that's
just a coincidence, right?
Sure.
Like the salt on the roads.
- Exactly.
- Hmm.
Congratulations on
your elegance, Cesare.
Congratulations
on your precision.
Mr. Fiorio, there's a problem.
We can't formalize
the victory yet.
What? What are we
supposed to do?
Put the corks back
in the champagne?
No, Fiorio. We're not joking.
Audi objected,
and at the very least we have
to evaluate it, you understand?
They claimed there was a
violation of the regulations.
You know how it works.
There's a disqualification
for this. That's how it is.
A violation? What are
you talking about?
This is a joke.
There was absolutely
no violation.
You exploited your relationship
with the authorities,
you had salt put on the road
and had the ice removed.
- That's a violation, Fiorio.
- No, it's not.
These are the regulations.
I know them by heart.
All right? Check for yourself.
It's not written anywhere.
It's not allowed,
but neither is it forbidden.
On you go, check.
Mr. Fiorio,
could you wait outside
for a moment, please?
He's right. If it's not
forbidden, it's allowed.
All right, let's sign this.
Come in.
There!
- The victory certificate.
- Thank you.
What else do you
want, Fiorio? Eh?
Do you have any aspirin?
I have a headache.
It's OK, sorry. Thank you.
- Good evening.
Mr. Fiorio, Lancia team manager.
I'm sorry, Fiorio. I'm sorry,
I cannot find you on the list.
If you search my name in the standings,
you'll find it in the first place.
In this list, I don't know.
The dress code is
jacket and tie.
Maybe we can find you jacket.
Are you feeling all right?
You don't, you
don't look so great.
Thanks. I think I
have a temperature.
- Have you taken anything?
- An aspirin.
Ask them for a grog. Hot
rum, honey and lemon.
Take my advice.
Hi.
- Hmm.
- See?
- Are you feeling better?
- Yeah.
What'd I tell you?
By the way, I'm Cesare.
Nice to meet you.
Fiorio, I know.
Is there anyone here
who doesn't know you?
Actually, the people at the
front door, but nevermind.
I mean, what are you
doing here in this circus?
Getting bored.
Well, in that case,
you should go home.
- Yeah.
- But what do you do in life?
I teach nutritional medicine
at the University of Grenoble.
Shall we have a toast?
- Well, did we really win?
- Yes.
Finally we win.
- Cheers.
I mean, it went well this
time, but you know, in Sweden,
I need you even more so.
Well, I'm not coming to Sweden.
Listen, I know you don't
care about, you know,
the driver's championship,
but I have to win.
I have to win the
constructors' one.
You understand
that? Is that clear?
That's your problem, not mine.
I told you that.
Excuse me for a moment,
I'll call you back.
Walter...
is refusing to go to Sweden.
What do you mean, refusing? It's
not like it's a company outing.
Don't ask me to explain,
it's complicated.
Don't ask me to convince
him. It's impossible.
You asked for him.
I was thinking... we could
simply not go to Sweden.
What do you mean,
not go to Sweden?
Let's pass this whim of
Walter's off as a team choice.
If he wants to stay home to make
honey, we have other drivers.
You know fine we can't win
in the snow without him.
If we stay home, the
Germans will get a fright.
Lancia is so strong
they can afford to skip a round.
- So are we withdrawing?
- No.
We're not withdrawing. We're just
moving in a different direction.
I've heard bullshit
before, but this really...
Not going to Sweden will
result in huge savings.
Do you know what
this circus costs?
Helicopters, planes,
trucks. 40 people to move.
With that money we
could develop the 037.
And win in Portugal.
You take the
responsibility for this.
But if it goes wrong...
But what if it goes well?
With this victory
you're sending a clear
signal to your rivals.
Even if Lancia didn't show
up, are you the team to beat?
Don't worry, sir,
we'll win in Portugal.
The road ahead is very long,
so it's too soon to
make any predictions.
Our rivals are more than
worthy of respect, thanks.
Are you referring to
anyone in particular?
No.
The wait is over. Here
we are, once again,
with the protagonists of
the 17th rally of Porto.
Walter Roöhrl's Lancia.
Wait, maybe there's
a problem for Roöhrl.
Welcome back, Walter.
Come on.
Well, back on course.
Roger.
10 seconds.
Go!
Fantastic.
As you were saying,
Audi has invested heavily to
become competitive in rallying,
and this year they're demonstrating
all their technical strength.
Yeah, but you know,
money and technology are not
enough to win in this sport.
So what do you need to win?
Heart and brain and a
pinch of creativity.
- Ah, talent.
- Hmm, I would say obsession.
Looking at the
constructors' standings,
Audi is ahead of Lancia.
So it doesn't seem
to me that this
obsession is giving you the
results that you wanted.
And yet you're still
fighting your partisan war.
In this business you're very
well known for being creative
and finding solutions
to help you win.
Who says that?
Listen, this is a sport
that's raced on the road.
And on the road, anything goes.
You've dominated the
industry for two decades.
In 1963, you founded
the High Fidelity team.
Do you still feel that you
can ensure this High Fidelity
to the company, to the team?
Yes, I can.
You're being very selfish.
It was a very hot day.
What did you expect?
I like you.
This is my profession.
This is who I am.
You want me in southern France,
drinking rose all the time.
No, no, no.
But this your permanent record,
but you've never been happy.
And I don't want
to live like this.
Sorry Roland, I'm tired.
Yo, stay here, Gloria.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Sure?
Yes, sure.
Why are you asking?
We are having a
party because we won.
You still think that the Germans
are only technology and
organization, don't you?
But don't believe all
the cliches, Fiorio.
Because with that car, you
will never win against me.
Another round?
Cheers!
Mr. Fiorio? We are ready.
Okay, let's go.
This year to award
the prize to Udo Kurt,
the young driver who stood out
in the Stewart McCoy Memorial,
ladies and gentlemen,
Cesare Fiorio.
We have also here tonight,
the daughter of the driver
who left us 20 years ago
in a tragic accident.
Ladies and gentlemen, I
ask a round of applause
to the beautiful Jane, daughter
of the great Stuart McCoy!
Now we can finally give to
the young driver the award.
Wow.
Thank you.
I, I'm very delighted to be
here. It's an honor for me.
When I started to
sign with Lancia,
it was like a dream come true
and an emotion that
is indescribable,
so thank you very much.
So, we meet again.
It's not that surprising, seeing
as we're on the same road.
I knew your father.
Yeah, it seems like everyone
did, and better than me.
I was too young
when it happened.
I remember exactly where I
was the day of the accident.
I don't wanna talk about it.
So, what are you doing here?
Getting bored here, too?
Listen, I was thinking,
I mean, I really need
a doctor on my team.
I need someone who takes
care of my drivers.
You know, diets,
physical conditions.
I think you are
the right person.
Look, I've spent my entire life trying
to keep my distance from racing.
I don't think it's a good idea.
I think it could be good
for you, if you join us, hm?
Also to fight boredom.
6:00 PM L'AVVOCATO CALLED
- Sir.
- What are you doing?
I understand how the
Audi's exhaust works.
They're made of titanium.
I mean, on a sedan...
so they have a long
car, long exhaust.
So, they've lightened it.
If we could mount the same
exhaust, we'd go faster.
Are you an engineer? A
designer? Do you have a degree?
- No, I thought...
- There, you mustn't think.
You mustn't think.
- It was about looking bad in Portugal.
- I heard you.
I looked like shit, not you.
It's me who looks like shit.
A brand like Fiat Lancia
cannot afford this look.
After these defeats, the last of
which I'd say was a humiliation,
the sponsors are starting
to threaten to pull out.
Justifying all this
money without any results
isn't what you promised me.
Remember that if you go, I go.
So find some way to
start winning again...
- Yes.
- If you're still able.
Don't worry, I'll find
a way, you'll see.
The revenge finally comes
for Cesare Fiorio
and his Lancia.
After two consecutive
defeats, they win in Corsica.
Mikkola's Audi was
soundly beaten.
The world championship
is thus reopened.
We're two minutes ahead.
We drove well and made
the right choices.
Hello, Mikkola.
How do you feel being
in second place?
Not good.
Not good. We are late
by about two minutes.
Do you think Audi will
be able to recover?
No.
You finished?
The solutions adopted by Fiorio
has begun to yield results.
Rumor has it they've managed
to lighten their exhaust.
Maybe the turning point
of the season has come
for the Italian manufacturer.
Telegram from L'Avvocato.
What happened here?
They were celebrating,
they had too much to drink.
No, they don't even have
the strength to drink.
Do they know you won?
It's like you lost.
L'Avvocato congratulates you. He
wants the same again in Greece.
We need to see if they
can make it to Greece.
What d'you mean?
I mean they're physically
broken, they're done in.
We need to do something.
Listen, wait a minute for me.
Hello?
Yes, can I speak with
Dr. McCoy please?
Jane, it's Cesare,
Cesare Fiorio.
You remember me?
Guys,
may I have your
attention please?
May I introduce to
you Dr. Jane McCoy.
She teaches nutritional science
at University of Bordeaux.
- Grenoble.
- Ah Grenoble, sorry.
- Good morning, everyone.
- Morning.
So from now on she will tell you
what to eat and what to drink.
More than anything else,
I'll be telling you what not
to eat and what not to drink.
She will also tell you
what time to go to
sleep, unfortunately.
Each of you will be examined
and have a personalized report.
I'll follow each of you
checking your biorhythms,
calculating your calorie
intake and vitamin needs.
As we know, we can't
afford any more mishaps.
The drivers have to always be
in peak physical condition.
Any questions?
Good, good.
Let's get to work, come on.
So this is where we're gonna
have the first service, okay?
Then the second and the third.
After this, we're gonna
have a long section,
road section, okay?
To reach this point after two
hours for the stop control.
And then we need to be in
Athens at nine, at the hotel.
You need to be there too,
to check the drivers over.
Yeah, sounds good.
Cesare,
you okay?
Yeah, I'm just thinking
About what?
Winning.
What are you doing?
Wait for me here.
Are you crazy?
We have to be at, the stop
control in less than an hour.
Precisely. In one hour.
Relax.
- Hello.
- Honey.
- Is yours?
Greek honey.
Smell this...
And, um.
I'll do it.
What, what material?
There is no time, Walter.
The other cars are coming.
Yes, okay, okay.
Otherwise we'll be penalized.
Don't be rude. I'll
be right there.
Elena, bring some honey.
Okay, I, I.
Thank you.
Get away, get away.
Hurry up.
Hurry up guys, get
away from here.
Hurry up please hurry up.
It's a fucking race rally.
Get out of the way.
No, no, wait, wait.
We are gonna be.
What are you doing?
This prick doesn't go
away with these sheep.
Greece.
What, what's happening now?
What is happening?
It's dead.
Okay, let me see.
Maybe it's an
electrical problem.
Come on, try again.
No, nothing, nothing.
Okay, give it a try.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Okay, go.
- Go, go.
This is base, communicate
your position, please.
Walter?
What is he doing?
We are in transfer not a race.
He wants to keep us back
so we arrive late
for the time check.
He wants us to get the penalty?
We'll be seeing if he succeeds.
Walter, this is base,
can you hear me?
Walter, where are you?
On our way, we're coming.
Are you crazy? You'll
get a puncture this way.
Okay, here you go.
Walter, I mean,
where have you been?
I tried to call
you on the radio.
Well done. Good job.
What did he say?
Nevermind.
Listen Udo, in Finland
you really fly.
The brake's more
important than the gas.
The way you control
the oversteer.
Walter, why are you
telling me this?
You want me to win the race?
I want you to get to the finish.
Take care.
You too.
Walter,
what did you say to Kurt?
I was wishing him
luck for Finland.
- Why?
- Because I like him.
What do you mean you like him?
I like him, He's a nice
guy. I wish him luck.
What's the problem?
Are you gonna come
to Finland or not?
No.
No, you are coming.
- No, I'm not.
- And don't say I told you.
But I did tell you,
that was the agreement.
What are you talking
about? What agreement?
Listen, why don't you
see that doing this
you're dropping the
whole team in the shit,
and handing the title to Audi.
Only losers always want to win.
Bullshit, come on man, bullshit.
You know what I think?
I think that you don't
want to come because,
because you're scared.
- Hmm?
- I'm scared.
Yes.
It's possible, maybe yes.
You know what the problem is?
It's you not being
scared enough,
because that car
isn't made for jumps.
You've lightened it too
much, you should know that.
You knew it before.
- Yes I did.
- You knew it before.
- I told you.
- Now we have a problem.
What do you do?
You're going away.
You let me down.
You leave me alone.
You know, okay okay, go.
Okay, fuck you
Walter. Fuck you.
You're fired.
You're fired. Go go.
You won't race, you're
not strong enough.
- I'm going to win in Finland.
- No, it's not the point.
Look, when we get to Turin,
I will examine you properly
and if there's even 1%
chance that you can race,
I'll let you do that.
Okay?
Okay.
Did you call me, sir?
Yes. Did you increase the
pressure of the volumetric?
Yes.
- New suspension?
- Yes. Ennio dealt with that.
OK. You can go, then. It's late.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
- Get some rest.
- Thank you.
- Do you need a lift?
- Yes, thanks.
I left my car gate 12.
Okay.
What are you doing still here?
I was waiting for the results
of the team's analysis.
Anyway,
how's it going?
Well, thanks.
Why?
I heard about Walter.
Yeah, doesn't want to
know. He doesn't care.
You can't always force someone
to do what they don't want do.
So.
Thanks.
Were you waiting for me?
I was a bit worried about you.
- Goodnight.
- Bye.
Thank you.
See? Even the door.
Now this way, follow
the finger please.
So, up.
Is he good?
Last checks, then
he is good to go.
Right.
Audi is showing
all its strength.
Okay, just follow here, far.
And back.
What are you doing?
Are you leaving?
Yeah, I'm, I'm done here.
I just need to go by the
university and finish some work.
I'll meet you guys in Sanremo.
What's wrong Cesare?
Nothing, I can't
find my stopwatch.
I think I left it in my hotel.
I can go and get it.
No, don't worry about
that. I can send someone.
I'll go.
I'm gonna go.
Room 64.
Yeah, okay.
All right?
- Yeah, you can go.
- Thanks.
Team Lancia, Room 64 please.
Meanwhile, the race is going on.
Michèle Mouton is the next
driver to start after Kurt.
Wait, Udo Kurt has a problem.
Okay, the Lancia driver has
apparently solved his problem
with the helmet.
How does an engine work?
Well there is a key, right?
And then you have petrol.
And when you turn
the key together
with a petrol, it makes
like a huge explosion.
That's how an engine
works. Understand?
Hey, wanna know
how engines work?
70.
Easy right.
Too hard.
Give it to me.
This is how four stroke internal
compression engines work.
Suction, compression,
explosion and discharge.
100.
Caution over the crest.
50, right, and opens.
20, left four junction.
Left, three.
20 and right, ease left three.
There's been an accident,
the car's on fire.
There's smoke.
Repeat. Who had an
accident, where?
It's impossible, look.
- That's an easy curve.
- It's the suspension. I'll go.
Vuda! Vuda!
Stop.
We're withdrawing.
So the co-driver is out danger.
What about Kurt's condition?
We'll wait to know for sure.
Okay. Thank you.
Cesare.
He's in a coma.
And?
To simplify it, if zero
is the vegetative state
from which it's
impossible to recover,
and 10 is coming out of a coma,
your driver is at one.
What can we do?
Medicine stops here.
I shouldn't say
this as a doctor,
now it's up to you.
What do you mean?
Let him know that you're there.
I trust you.
I heard from L'Avvocato.
He was very sorry
about the accident.
The insurance company will
make a payout to Kurt's family.
- Did you find her?
- No, and no one's seen her.
Go.
The board has already told me
they don't intend to
renew the racing budget
for next year.
There might not be a next year.
Let's face it,
Cesare, like you say:
no one wants to buy
a car that loses,
let alone one you die in.
He's still alive.
You raced as a driver in
the 1961 Monte Carlo rally,
but you didn't complete
because of an accident.
Did you become a team manager
because you were scared?
Sorry, I don't understand
what you're getting at.
You have your drivers
racing in prototypes,
normal cars that have
been pushed to the max
to become really
powerful beasts.
Do you not feel a sense of
responsibility for your driver
who was just involved
in an accident?
Obviously I'm very
worried about the guy,
but to eliminate
risk from rallying
would be eliminate
rallying itself.
Earlier you compared
rallying to war.
So let me quote
something for you.
In the "Art of
War," Sun Tzu writes
that it's possible
to know how to win
without actually winning.
Is that what's happening to you?
I see you still don't
understand how this sport works.
Here, you don't race to
overtake the other guy.
You race against the clock,
and if you lose, you
lose against yourself.
Is that how you feel right now?
What do you mean?
Like someone who's
going to withdraw
because he's lost
against himself.
Love! Come, the cake!
Coming.
Sorry, I have to go.
It's been a pleasure.
Pleasure. Thank you.
Thank you.
♪ What a difference
a day makes ♪
♪ 24 little hours ♪
♪ Brought the sun
and the flowers ♪
♪ Where there used to be rain ♪
♪ My yesterday was blue dear ♪
♪ Today I'm a part
of you, dear ♪
♪ My lonely nights
are through, dear ♪
I see, you've already
signed up for them.
If you want to beat them,
you have to first
get to know them.
What are you celebrating?
Birthday, my son.
What are you doing here?
Beehives.
There's a really good craftsman
here in Turin, the best.
Sure.
Has the suspension collapsed?
Yeah.
How are you?
Fine.
Okay.
That's what I wanted to hear.
See you at Sanremo.
Hard right. Left.
Hard left, left,
and right, five.
100, medium long left.
- Good morning sir.
- Okay.
Audi was also very
fast on the asphalt.
Now we have the second
stage in Tuscany.
Ennio is coordinating
service trucks here and here.
Then we have 200
kilometers of dirt road.
In order to be at the stop
control in Liguria at 12:45.
All clear?
Yes sir.
Good. Let's go.
Come on.
Any news from Kurt?
No.
- Go!
Mikkola's Audi
Quattro taking off.
All right, what's the time?
Three, two, one. Go!
Fifty right, then a left open.
70 right, three 120.
Walter is first, second Mikkola,
third and fourth
Alen and Vudafieri.
The Germans are surrounded.
Be sure they have some rest.
Yeah, I'll make them
a herbal tea tonight,
help them sleep.
And I've got some maltodextrins
for them in the morning.
- What are they?
- Relax.
They're just water-soluble
complex carbohydrates.
You know what to
do. It's your job.
Yeah. And what's yours?
Mine? My job is to win.
Why is it so important?
I've been with you guys
for a while now and I,
I still don't understand it.
Don't try to understand.
If you try to understand,
you will never win.
But why do you do it?
I mean the drivers, my father.
Why do they risk their
lives just to win?
- There's more to it.
- What more is there than life?
Racing to go nowhere.
Where is not the point.
The point is how.
As fast as you can.
And death?
Is it worth it?
Death is afraid of
those who pursue it.
Instead of waiting for it,
we run after it,
and it moves away.
Jane?
Thanks.
Thank you for what
you're doing for us.
Roöhrl should arrive
at the time control
10 minutes earlier.
Okay, see you at the checkpoint.
What's going on?
What's wrong man?
During the road section
I felt a vibration
of the clutch pedal.
Sinister noise, so I stopped.
I think it's the bearing.
It's the bearing.
So change it.
We can't.
What do you mean we can't?
We don't have another one.
Why don't we have
another one, sorry?
Sir, in 10 years of rallying,
I've never seen a broken bushing.
Do you realize
what you're saying?
It's like a pilot not having a
parachute because he's never crashed!
Even if we had one...
We have to be at
the stop control...
At 12.45, I know what time we need
to be there, is that clear? I know.
12.45.
Okay.
Excuse me, are you saying if we had
another bearing you could change it?
If we had one, technically
it would be possible.
There, you see? You
only need to ask.
- Vuda, come on!
- Sir, again? What's going on?
Nothing. We need your
car. We need the bushing.
Come on, go take
a shower, go on.
Sir, that way Mikkola's
first and Alén second.
Vudafieri would be third, the first
podium of his life. It's not fair.
You have 50 minutes
to change the bushing.
49.
- That's not how you win.
- What did you say?
- So what is?
- Do you know how to win?
- No, but not like that.
- What do you know about winning?
- I'm not doing it.
Are you kidding?
- What did you say, sorry?
- I'm not doing it.
Cesare.
They just called me
from the hospital,
Kurt's back with us again.
Kurt is back.
He's back with us again.
Change this fucking bushing.
Let's go, we have an hour,
come on. Come on, quick.
Brake, like that.
We're almost done.
- Done.
- Come on!
Walter, you have to fly, okay?
You're on time.
So now we're at the final stage.
Good strong team, so
we're sure to win.
Mikkola is our strongest player.
Sir, from here, the
weather is variable.
There could be
communication problems.
Sir? Sir, can you hear me?
Here we are at the last stage
of the rally out of Sanremo.
Sir? Sir, can you hear me?
What did you say, can you
repeat please? I can't hear you.
There could be
communication problems.
I'll keep you updated.
Okay, let's stay in touch.
Fiorio's Lancia
and Gumpert's Audi
play it all out
in one last stage.
Whoever wins today will conquer
the 1983 Constructors'
Championship.
Mikkola leads the championship
and seems to be the favorite.
Alen, second Lancia driver.
And finally, Roöhrl.
Will he be able to defeat Audi?
Today we are making
history here.
Go.
Mr. Fiorio, I can
see Roöhrl's Lancia.
He is driving very well.
According to intermediate time,
Roöhrl has 12 seconds
lead over Mikkola.
12 seconds ahead.
Okay.
Now the road is wet.
It's more difficult.
Roöhrl might lose a few seconds.
Walter, can you hear me?
Walter?
Push on that
fucking pedal, okay?
Because we can still do it.
Mikkola is ahead.
It's not the time to give up.
Give everything you can.
You must recover 10 seconds.
Push, push, push,
it's now or never.
Okay.
Good.
There is smoke!
I cannot hear you. Repeat.
There was smoke. I can't see.
There is smoke. A
car caught fire.
Whose car has caught fire?
I don't understand,
I can't see well.
I can't tell if it's
Mikkola or Roöhrl's Lancia.
Walter? Walter, can hear me?
Can you hear me? Walter, please!
Are you crazy, Walter?
Why are you slowing down?
Walter we're gonna
lose the race.
Alén crosses the
finish line first
and wins the Constructors'
Championship for Lancia.
Mikkola is out of the race.
This is rallying.
Are you happy? You won.
You should be happy
too, you didn't.
Only losers always
wanna win, don't they?
That's right.
They are happy.
We are not happy.
Next season.
Crazy, yes we are very,
very happy, as you can see.
We did not expect to win.